[
  {
    "question": "Is the same key used for both authentication and encryption in WEP?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "Yes",
      "No",
      "Yes, if 802.1X authentication is not used",
      "The same key is never used twice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How does WEP detect replay?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "There is no replay detection",
      "By the intialization vector (TV)",
      "By the integrity check value (ICV)",
      "By the random nonce value (RNV)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How long is the IV used in TKIP?",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["24 bits", "48 bits", "64 bits", "128 bits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol encapsulates the EAP messages transported between the supplicant and authenticator in WPA/RSN?",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["EAP-TLS", "EAPOL", "802.11", "802.1X"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the first phase of PEAP?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "The supplicant provides the identity to the authentication server",
      "The supplicant and authentication server negotiate the EAP method to be used",
      "The supplicant encrypt and communicate the password to the authenticator",
      "Supplicant establishes an authenticated secrecy channel to the authentication server"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 802.11 frame type is cryptographically protected by the 802.11w standard?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "Management frames",
      "Control frames",
      "Data frames",
      "Beacon frames"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the 128 bits start value of the counter for CCMP encryption initialized in RSN?",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": [
      "By a random IV",
      "By the concatenation of IV and the extended IV",
      "By the concatenation of flag/priority bits, packetnumber, source-address, and a constant",
      "By source address, destination address and the MIC value of the MPDU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the key size of AES as used in RSN?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["128 bits", "192 bits", "256 bits", "512 bits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does EAP-SIM provide mutual authentication?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "No, it uses the regular GSM authentication",
      "Yes, it uses the regular UMTS authentication",
      "Yes, by the regular GSM authentication and the authentication token from the AuC",
      "Yes, by the regular GSM authentication and a nonce in the encrypted AP response"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the EAPOL 4-way handshake?",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": [
      "To exchange a fresh pairwise temporal key (PTK) from the pairwise master key (PMK)",
      "To exchange a fresh pairwise message key (PMK) from the pairwise transient key (PTK)",
      "To exchange a fresh pairwise transient key (PTK) from the pairwise master key (PMK) with bilateral key agreement and group key transfer",
      "To exchange a fresh pairwise message key (PMK) from the pairwise trusted key (PTK) generated in the 4-way key agreement including group key distribution"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the four types of EAPOL messages used in WPA/RSN?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "Start, Key, Packet, Logoff",
      "Request, Authenticate, Result, Stop",
      "Identity, Challenge, Response, Accept",
      "Logon, Name, Password, Logoff"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the sequence number (SQN) used in 3G/UMTS networks?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "The USIM can detect replay of authentication messages",
      "The VLR/SGSN can detect replay of authentication messages",
      "The UE can verify the MAC values by using f1",
      "The HLR/AuC can generate distinct session keys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "List the message authentication code types used in UMTS",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": ["MIC, MAC", "MAC-A, MAC-I, MAC-S", "IK, AK", "AUTIN, AUTS"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the three most important security services in GSM?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "User authentication, radio channel confidentiality, and temporary identities",
      "Subscriber Identity Module, Visiting Location Register, and Authentication Centre",
      "User identification, end-to-end encryption, and symmetric key exchange",
      "The cryptographic algorithms A3, A5 and A8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the variables of the authentication token (AUTN) used in UMTS networks?",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": [
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>AK</mi></math>, <math><mi>XRES</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC</mi></math>",
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>AK</mi></math>, <math><mi>AMF</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC</mi></math>",
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi></math>, <math><mi>AMF</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC</mi></math>, <math><mi>RAND</mi></math>",
      "<math><mi>SQN</mi><mo>&#x2295;</mo><mi>AK</mi></math>, <math><mi>AMF</mi></math>, <math><mi>MAC</mi></math>, <math><mi>RAND</mi></math>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which UTRAN layers provide encryption?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "MAC layer and RRC layer",
      "RLC layer and RRC layer",
      "PHY layer and MAC layer",
      "MAC layer and RLC layer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which UTRAN layer provides integrity protection?",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": ["MAC layer", "RLC layer", "RRC layer", "PHY layer"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a call session control function (CSCF)?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "A SIP server or proxy used in IMS",
      "A Mobile Switching Centre (MSC) with IMS support",
      "A GPRS Support Node (GSN) with IMS support",
      "A Real-time Transport Protocol (RTP) session controller used in IMS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the length of the cipher key CK used in UMTS?",
    "answers": [2],
    "options": ["56 bits", "64 bits", "128 bits", "256 bits"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many rounds does the KASUMI cipher use?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": ["8", "10", "12", "16"]
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of cipher is KASUMI?",
    "answers": [1],
    "options": [
      "Stream cipher",
      "Feistel cipher",
      "Substitution-permutation cipher",
      "Nonlinear feedback shiftregister cipher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is the UICC normally easily removable from the mobile station?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "The USIM holds an expiration date and, like credit cards, must be replaced",
      "The failure rate of the integrated circuit cards (UICCs) are high because the issuers (mobile operators) want to optimize cost against subscription duration",
      "End-to-end UMTS key-card plugs into the USIM slot for key distribution and management",
      "The UE manufacturing and lifecycle can be managed independently from the personalization and subscription process"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why must the USIM implementation be tamper-proof?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "To facilitate the mobile operator with secure computation and storage at the UE side",
      "To protect the proprietary crypto-algorithms of the mobile operator",
      "To protect the subscriber against unauthorized modification of the subscription parameters",
      "To provide the subscriber with a PIN-protected access to the UMTS service"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is a oneway hash function useful in digital forensic investigations?",
    "answers": [0],
    "options": [
      "For fast recognition of known file content",
      "For reconstructing the hash tables of deleted files",
      "For juridical determination of incriminating file content",
      "For legally sound presentation of the digital evidence"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the MILENAGE functions in UMTS?",
    "answers": [3],
    "options": [
      "Block cipher family of functions that build the algorithms for integrity code and the encryption process",
      "Transformation of keys for the inter-operation of GSM and UMTS basestations and net works",
      "Pseudorandom generators that output the initializing values for the cryptographic computations",
      "Algorithms for computing the cryptographic variables needed in the mutual authentication protocols"
    ]
  }
]
